igames.org 2006-06-15

# iGAMES ONLINE PRIVACY STATEMENT

******iGAMES ONLINE PRIVACY STATEMENT**

****Last updated August 8, 2005

**Welcome to iGames!**

**OUR PRIVACY COMMITMENT**

iGames respects the privacy rights of our online visitors and recognizes the importance of protecting all information that you may choose to share with us.

We also recognize the need to provide additional protections for children who visit our sites. To read about our privacy protections for kids under the age of 13, click here to read iGames’ Kids Online Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Statement and the certification seal shown on this page confirms that iGames is a valid member in ESRB’s Privacy Online Program. ESRB’s Privacy Online Program is designed to ensure that our website’s information collection practices are responsible and appropriate. To protect your privacy, we have voluntarily undertaken this privacy initiative and all of our websites have been reviewed and certified by ESRB Privacy Online to meet established online information collection and use practices. As part of this privacy program, we are subject to frequent audits of our sites and other enforcement and accountability mechanisms administered independently by the ESRB.

**TABLE OF CONTENTS**

**Q1. What information does this Privacy Statement cover?  
Q2. What types of Personal Information do we collect about our guests?  
Q3. How is your Personal Information used and shared?  
Q4. What choices do you have about the collection, use, and sharing of your Personal Information?  
Q5. What kinds of security measures do we take to safeguard your Personal Information?  
Q6. How can you update your Personal Information and profile?  
Q7. How can you ask questions, or send us comments, about this Privacy Policy?  
Q8. How will you know if we amend this Privacy Policy? **

|  | **What information does this Privacy Statement cover?**  
---|---  
| This Privacy Policy, part of our overall Terms of Service, describes how iGames uses personally identifiable information regarding our members which is defined as any information that identifies you or may be used to contact you (such as name, address, and email addresses) (“ **Personal Information** ”) collected through the domain and sub-domains of [www.igames.org](http://www.igames.org/) (the “ **Site** ”) as part of the registration process or otherwise in connection with your use of the various services (the “ **Service** ”) offered by iGames through the Site. 

Finally, the terms of this Privacy Policy are subject to all applicable laws.

back to top ****  
  
| **What types of personally identifiable information do we collect about our guests?**  
| We collect several types of Personal Information about our guests. We don’t require Personal Information to access our site. However, if you prefer not to disclose Personal Information, you will not be able to enjoy certain features of our site. 

**Information You Provide to Us**

Much of the Personal Information we collect comes directly from our web guests. Typically, this information includes name, credit card number, postal and email address, telephone, cell and facsimile number. Additionally, we may also collect other types of non-personal information (known as demographic information) such as your gender, age, date of birth, country, favorite video game, and gaming platform. This demographic information may be associated with your Personal Information and will be used to communicate with you. 

**We collect Personal Information from our web guests to:**

  1. Register for the Service
  2. Register for Game Centers
  3. Register for iGames Communities
  4. Participate in Events
  5. Promotions, surveys, or questionnaires
  6. Questions and Customer Support

**Events.** Game center members have the ability to initiate events, including tournaments, through the Service. To create such events through the Service, iGames requires Personal Information from the sponsoring game center. If gamer members wish to participate in such events, they will be required to provide certain Personal Information and may be asked to provide additional, optional, information. In addition, if the event is one for which iGames rankings are available (this is disclosed at the time of registration), iGames will collect the results of the event and incorporate them into the iGames rankings for the particular games. The rankings will indicate the relative standing of each participant for the particular game.

**Promotions.** We may occasionally run optional contests, surveys, or other special promotions on the Service in which we ask participants for Personal Information or demographic information (like a zip code, age or favorite video game). We may use the data we collect in these contests and promotions to send you promotional material about iGames or third parties. Your Personal Information collected from these contests and promotions may be used to contact you when necessary and may be shared with other companies for promotional purposes, but only under the terms and conditions specified when you take part in the promotion.

Whatever the purpose may be, we will only collect information to the extent reasonably necessary to fulfill your requests and our legitimate business objectives.

**Business Information**

For practical reasons, we treat Personal Information submitted to us in a business capacity different from information we receive in a non-business capacity. Personal Information submitted to us in a business capacity (e.g. resumes) may be shared with third parties, depending on the nature of the inquiry.

**Information Collected Through Technology**

We collect information through technology to make our sites more interesting and useful to you. For example, when you come to one of our sites, we collect your IP address. An IP address is often associated with the portal through which you enter the Internet, like your ISP (Internet service provider), your company, or your university. Standing alone, your IP address is not personally identifiable. At times, we also use IP addresses to collect information regarding the frequency with which our guests visit various parts of our sites. We may combine this information with personally identifiable information.

**Network Advertisers**

Many advertisements are managed and placed on our website by third parties. These companies are called "network advertisers." Network advertisers who place advertisements on 

our website may also use cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information when you click on or move your cursor over one of their banner advertisements. You may not realize this information is being collected. In some cases, we may have access to information from Web beacons and cookies used by network advertisers on our sites and this information may permit us to identify other sites that you have visited that are also associated with the network advertiser. Finally, once you've clicked on an advertisement and have left our Web sites, our Privacy Policy no longer applies and you must read the privacy policy of the advertiser to see how your Personal Information will be handled on their site. 

**Cookies**

Our website also uses cookies. Cookies are pieces of information that a website sends to your computer while you are viewing the website. We and other companies use cookies for a variety of purposes. For example, when you return to one of our sites after logging in, cookies provide information to the site so that the site will remember who you are. You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You can do this through your browser (like Netscape Navigator or Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies. If you turn cookies off, you won't have access to many features that make your web experience smoother, like the features mentioned above, and some of our services may not function properly.

**Web Beacons**

Our websites use a variety of technical methods for tracking purposes, including web beacons. Web beacons are small pieces of data that are embedded in images on the pages of web sites. We also use these technical methods to analyze the traffic patterns on our web sites, such as the frequency with which our users visit various parts of our Web sites. These technical methods may involve the transmission of information either directly to us or to another party authorized by us to collect information on our behalf. We also use these technical methods in HTML e-mails that we send our guests to determine whether our guests have opened those e-mails or clicked on links in those e-mails. The information from use of these technical methods may be collected in a form that is personally identifiable.

back to top ****  
  
| **How is your Personal Information used and shared?**  
| As described in detail below, iGames may use your Personal Information in many ways, including contacting you, sending you promotional materials, and sharing your information with third parties so that these third parties can send you promotional materials. By “promotional materials,” we mean communications that directly promote the use of our website, or the purchase of products or services. As outlined below in A4, you may "opt-out" of certain uses of your Personal Information 

**Game Centers.** If you are a member gamer and you indicate, when registering or by updating your account information, that you have a “home game center” which is a member of iGames, then we will provide to that game center Personal Information about you so that game center may contact you about its activities, promotions, and other matters which they believe may be of interest to you.

If you participate in an event sponsored by a particular game center member, your Personal Information will be provided to such game center in order to operate the event and report the results. That game center also may use your Personal Information to contact you about its other activities, promotions and other matters which they believe may be of interest to you.

Each game center member has agreed that it may only use the Personal Information it receives from iGames in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy. However, iGames is unable to guarantee that this will be the case. If you don’t want your Personal Information provided to a game center, then do not designate a “home game center,” and do not participate in game center sponsored events.

**Game Publishers, Advertisers, Etc.** We collect Personal Information and disclose it in an aggregate (non-personally identifiable) manner to game publishers, advertisers, and other third parties for marketing and promotional purposes. We also share this aggregate information to enable these companies to understand the number and composition of the iGames members and their use of our Service. In these situations, we don’t disclose to these entities any Personal Information. However, if you respond to ads provided by an advertiser they may assume that you fit a certain demographic profile based on the aggregate information provided to them. In addition, when you click on a banner ad, you should be aware that the advertiser may be collecting information from you.

**Operational Uses**

We may also use your Personal Information for other purposes such as "Operational Uses." For example, we may use your information to send you administrative communications either about your account with us or about features of our websites, including any future changes to this Privacy Policy.

Finally, we may take your Personal Information and make it non-personally identifiable, either by combining it with information about other individuals (aggregating your information with information about other individuals), or by removing characteristics (such as your name) that make the information personally identifiable to you (de-personalizing your information). Given the nature of this information, no restrictions apply under this Privacy Policy on our right to aggregate or de-personalize your Personal Information, and we may use and share in any way with third parties the resulting non-personally identifiable information.

**Purchase or Sale of Businesses**

From time to time, we may purchase a business or sell one or more of our businesses and your Personal Information may be transferred as a part of the purchase or sale. If we purchase a business, the Personal Information received with that business would be treated in accordance with this Privacy Policy, if it is practicable and permissible to do so. If we sell a business, we will include provisions in the selling contract requiring the purchaser to treat your Personal Information in the same manner required by this Privacy Policy (including any amendments to this Privacy Policy). The provisions of this paragraph will also apply if we are sold as part of bankruptcy proceedings.

**Disclosures Required By Law and Disclosures to Help Protect the Security and Safety of Our Websites and Others**

We will disclose Personal Information when we believe in good faith that such disclosures (a) are required by law, including, for example, to comply with a court order or subpoena, or (b) will help to: enforce our Terms of Use; enforce contest, sweepstakes, promotions, or game rules; protect your safety or security, including the safety and security of property that belongs to you; or protect the safety and security of our websites or third parties.

back to top ****  

| **What choices do you have about the collection, use, and sharing of your Personal Information?**  
| Generally, you have control over the Personal Information you submit to us. 

We encourage iGames members to update and edit their contact information and keep it current. You can easily correct or update contact and account information, or delete optional information in the preferences menu at any time, by using your login and password to access your iGames account. In addition, parents can review and edit information as well as delete optional information about their child’s iGames’ contact information, account information, and membership through the same method.

During registration, we also provide our game center members with the option to “Opt In” to having Personal Information shared with third parties so that those third parties may use your information to contact you about promotional materials, product information special offers, and other communications. The game center member must physically select to “Opt-In” either during the registration process or when updating their profile. To remove yourself from “Opt-In,” you must deselect this option from your profile page. 

If at any time you decide to remove your Personal Information from our database, you may do so by visiting the profile section of your iGames account or contacting us at [privacy@igames.org](mailto:privacy@igames.org). Even though your account will not be active, we may also retain your information in back-up storage for some period of time after your deletion request.

back to top ****  

| **What kinds of security measures do we take to safeguard your Personal Information?**  
| 

The security and confidentiality of your information is extremely important to us. We have implemented technical, administrative, and physical security measures to protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access and improper use. From time to time, we review our security procedures to consider appropriate new technology and methods. However, please understand that, despite our best efforts, no security measure is perfect or impenetrable.

Your membership account is password-protected. We strongly recommend that you do not give your password to anyone and that you change it every 3 months. If you are using a public computer or a shared computer, we strongly recommend that you sign out of your iGames account and close your browser before getting up and moving away from the computer. 

back to top ****  
  
| **How can you update your Personal Information and profile?**  
| 

You can access and update the contact information you gave us during registration (that is, your e-mail address or any other information that would directly enable us to contact you), by visiting the profile section of your iGames account or contacting us at [info@igames.org](mailto:info@igames.org).

back to top ****  
  
| **How can you ask questions, or send us comments about this Privacy Policy?**  
| If you have questions or wish to send us comments about this Privacy Policy, please send an e-mail with your questions or comments to [privacy@igames.org](mailto:privacy@igames.org) or write us: 

> iGames, Inc.  
>  Attn.: Privacy Administrator  
>  201 San Antonio Circle, Suite 250  
>  Mountain View, CA 94040  
>  (650) 917-9888

Please be assured that any Personal Information that you provide in communications to the above email and postal mail addresses will not be used to send you promotional materials, unless you request it.

iGames is a licensee of the ESRB’s Privacy Online Program. If you believe that we have not responded to your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, please contact ESRB at <http://www.esrb.org/privacy_wc_hotline.asp>.

> ESRB  
>  Attn.: Privacy Online Program  
>  317 Madison Avenue, 22nd Floor  
>  New York, NY 10017  
>  212-759-0700  

**Your California Privacy Rights**

Beginning on January 1, 2005, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of iGames who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of Personal Information to third parties for direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to [caprivacy@igames.org](mailto:caprivacy@igames.org) or write us: 

> iGames, Inc.   
>  Attn: CA Privacy Rights Administrator  
>  201 San Antonio Circle, Suite 250  
>  Mountain View, CA 94040  
> 

 back to top ****  

| **How will you know if we amend this Privacy Policy?**  
| We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make any material changes in the way we collect, use, or share your Personal Information, we will notify you by sending you an email at the last email address that you provided us, or by prominently posting notice of the changes on the websites covered by this Privacy Policy. Any material changes to this Privacy Policy will be effective 30 days following our dispatch of an email notice to you or 30 days following our posting of notice of the changes on the websites covered by this Privacy Policy. 

Please note that, at all times, you are responsible for updating your Personal Information to provide us your current email address. If the last email address that you have provided us is not valid, or for any other reason is not capable of delivering to you the notice described above, our dispatch of the email containing such notice will nonetheless constitute effective notice of the changes described in the notice.

back to top  

**iGAMES KIDS ONLINE PRIVACY STATEMENT**

Last updated August 8, 2005

**Welcome to iGames!**

**OUR PRIVACY COMMITMENT**

iGames has developed its website with the goal of creating an enjoyable experience for all users. This Kids Privacy Statement is designed to answer your questions regarding our privacy policies and principles with respect to children under the age of 13.

Building on our general Privacy Policy, we recognize the need to provide additional privacy protections when children visit the sites on which this Kids' Privacy Statement is posted. We explain those additional protections in this Kids' Privacy Statement.

The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”) requires that we inform parents and legal guardians about how we collect, use, and disclose personal information from children under 13 years of age; and that we obtain the consent of parents and guardians in order for children under 13 years of age to use certain features of our website. Below we explain how we do that for these “kids.” Also, when we use the term “parent” below, we mean to include legal guardians.

This Privacy Statement and the certification seal shown on this page confirms that iGames is a valid member in [ESRB’s Privacy Online Program](http://www.esrb.org/privacy.asp). ESRB’s Privacy Online Program is designed to alleviate consumers’ privacy concerns by ensuring a website’s information disclosure practices are responsible and appropriate. 

**TABLE OF CONTENTS**

**Q1. What types of information do we collect about kids?  
Q2. How do we use and share the personally identifiable information that we collect from kids?  
Q3. How do we notify and obtain consent from parents for the collection of personal information from their kids?  
Q4. How can parents access, change or delete personally identifiable information about their kids?  
Q5. What kinds of security measures do we take to safeguard kids’ personally identifiable information?  
Q6. How will we notify parents if our Kids’ Privacy Statement changes?  
Q7. Who do guests contact with questions or concerns about our Kids’ Privacy Statement? **

| **What types of information do we collect about kids?**  
---|---  
| 

Kids can surf iGames’ site, view content, and enjoy many features without any personal information being collected. We don’t collect personal information from kids unless they register on iGames’ site. Typically, kids will register to participate in the iGames community or engage in promotional activities (contests, newsletters, or surveys) or other special activities. As part of the registration process, we collect basic contact information from kids: child’s and parent’s name and e-mail address. We do not collect any other personally identifiable information from kids during our registration process. 

Once a child is registered, we may collect demographic information (date of birth, gender, and preferences) and combine it with the child’s personal information. iGames will only collect this information if it is voluntarily properly submitted to us by either the child or parent.

Note that all commercial sites directed to children under 13 are prohibited by U.S. law from conditioning a kid's participation in an online activity on the kid's providing more personal information than is reasonably necessary.

Some areas of our website offer features that allow kids to submit personal information (e.g., email address) without first disclosing their age or obtaining verifiable parental consent. These areas of our website provide services in a way that do not require prior verifiable parental consent.

Finally, we may collect demographic information about a kid. For example, if a kid participates in a survey, we may collect those responses. Among them, we may collect age, gender, hobbies, and interests or other demographic information about gaming and preferences. We also use some passive technologies, including cookies and web beacons, to monitor traffic on our websites. This demographic information may be associated with a child’s personal information.

back to top ****  
  
| **How do we use and share the personally identifiable information that we collect from kids?**  
| 

We may collect personal information from parents to allow kids to participate in certain activities offered on our website and through game center members. These activities may include contests, promotional information about new products and features, special offers, and other interesting events.

Other website features include e-mail, newsletters, news postings, events (such as game showcases and tournaments) at member game centers, promotions and other similar activities. In the course of a kid's participation in these features, a kid may also provide us additional information about himself or herself. If a parent allows us to collect personal information about their kid, we may link certain information collected through technology (see the "Information Collected Through Technology" section of A2 of our General Privacy Policy) to that personal information.

If a kid registers on the iGames website to participate in an event sponsored by a particular game center member, the kid’s name and email address will be provided to such game center in order to operate the event and report the results. That game center also may the kid’s personal information to contact the kid about its other activities, promotions and other matters which they believe may be of interest.

To protect kids, iGames will not allow children to select a “home” game center (which automatically provides the game center with the information collected during player registration). 

We may use the information that we collect from and about kids for our business purposes, including record-keeping, transaction fulfillment, and marketing. The contact information gathered from a kid is used to obtain consent to our information collection from their parents.

After registration, contact information may also be used to notify users of promotional activities such as contests, sweepstakes, newsletters or new products, or functional changes to our website or privacy policy. Finally, we may use personal and demographic information for our internal marketing and study ways to better improve our services.

If a kid wins a contest, we notify the parent at the email address provided to us during the registration process, and request that the parent provide his or her postal address for purposes of delivering the prize. We may publish a winner’s first name, city, and state of residence on our web site.

From time to time, iGames may share kids’ personal information with outside entities hired to assist with internal website support operations (e.g., online product fulfillment, email services, or technical support). These entities will not use kids’ personal information for any other purpose, and have agreed to maintain the confidentiality, security, and integrity of all the personal information they obtain from us. 

We don’t share any information about a kid with any third parties unless the disclosure is reasonably necessary to:  
• comply with law, including, for example, to comply with a court order or subpoena.  
• enforce our Terms of Service, or site or game rules.  
• protect the safety and security of our Guests and our website.

back to top ****  
  
| **How do we notify and obtain consent from parents for the collection of personal information from their kids?**  
| 

When a child attempts to register with our website, we send their parent an e-mail notifying them that their child would like to register, informing them of our privacy practices, and providing them with a consent form that must be mailed or faxed back to iGames. If the parent ignores or refuses to register their child, we will delete all contact information from our database. If the parent permits the registration, their child will be granted access to the features described in the notification e-mail.

back to top ****  

| **How can parents access, change or delete personally identifiable information about their kids?**  
| 

At any time, a parent can access, change, or delete the personal information that we have collected from his or her kid through their kid’s iGames login and password account or by contacting our customer service department through an e-mail to [privacy@igames.org](mailto:privacy@igames.org). Please include the kid member’s name and the parent's e-mail address in the e-mail so that we can better assist you with your inquiry or request.

back to top ****  

| **What kinds of security measures do we take to safeguard kids’ personally identifiable information?**  
| 

We take the security and confidentiality of kids’ information very seriously. We have implemented technical, administrative, and physical security measures to protect kids’ personal information from unauthorized access and improper use. From time to time, we review our security procedures to consider appropriate new technology and methods. However, please understand that, despite our best efforts, no security measure is perfect or impenetrable.

back to top ****  
  
| **How will we notify parents if our Kids’ Privacy Statement changes?**  
| 

We may amend our Kids' Privacy Statement at any time. We will provide parents notice by e-mail of any material changes in the way we intend to collect, use, or share kids' personal information. Please note that, at all times, parents should update their personal information to provide us current e-mail addresses. We will apply material changes in our Kids' Privacy Statement only in conformance with applicable law, including any applicable provisions of COPPA that require parental consent.

back to top ****  
  
| **Who do guests contact with questions or concerns about our Kids’ Privacy Statement?**  
| 

If you have questions or wish to send us comments about this Privacy Statement, please send an e-mail with your questions or comments to [privacy@igames.org](mailto:privacy@igames.org) or write us:

> iGames, Inc.  
>  Attn.: Privacy Administrator  
>  201 San Antonio Circle, Suite 250  
>  Mountain View, CA 94040  
>  (650) 917-9888

Please be assured that any Personal Information that you provide in communications to the above email and postal mail addresses will not be used to send you promotional materials, unless you request it.

iGames is a licensee of the ESRB’s Privacy Online Program. If you believe that we have not responded to your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, please contact ESRB at <http://www.esrb.org/privacy_wc_hotline.asp>

> ESRB  
>  Attn.: Privacy Online Program  
>  317 Madison Avenue, 22nd Floor  
>  New York, NY 10017  
>  212-759-0700  

back to top
